I move right into now the regular meeting of the City Council for today's day.
Item number two, recognition of Scott Miller for certification of open home,
a closing forcement association, Scott and Travis.
You got a come-up here.
You're a speech.
And you're just getting an award for being here a long time?
Yeah.
15 years of things?
Has a little more hair than me?
Scott recently completed early December his code enforcement certification at Climacy.
He made his our fifth officer and our department.
And that was one of our goals for this year's get five certified code enforcement officers.
He recently took over the duties full-time and he recently implemented a route for our code enforcement.
Not that.
But it didn't work before, but now hopefully we can measure our progress a little better.
What do you want to say?
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I was really a public input on schedule for personal services.
We wanted to see what you should address the council on any of the agenda.
I'm forced to send in the staff.
I was up many items five through 15 for the consent of campus.
There are no questions of this line.
We need to go to the items of their family motion.
Most people are in there.
And the second.
For all of this?
Duncan?
Um.
With a four-ster.
Uh.
Western.
Aye.
So?
Act.
That takes us to the item of 16.
Presentation by Arden and Associates of the fiscal year 15, 16 August,
financial statements, and an independent auditor for four.
Is it problem on how are you tonight?
Are you Andy?
Hi, Andy.
In that pronounce that line.
You did.
All right.
Welcome to my end.
Well, thank you.
Good evening, all.
My name is Andy Kromer.
I'm a CPN one of the odd partners with Arden and Associates.
We're out of Edmund.
And we've just completed your 2016 audit.
And I just want to take a minute to tell you who we are and who we are not.
This is the first year we've done your audit.
We did it maybe five or six, seven years ago.
All along, you all have been using Crawford and Associates.
I look on the city.
There are a separate CPA firm in the house.
They come in and help you all get ready for audit.
They may help you there in the year with certain things, budgets and maybe special projects.
As you see that, to be, you know, see that to be needed.
But again, they are a different firm than us, different ownership.
We have a similar work in arrangement with them on a number of cities.
But they do excellent work.
But again, just to know we're separate from them.
You should have two documents.
The first one is the big financial.
report. It's found. You got a nice cover on it. Let's get submitted to this state. It has
been submitted to this state. And I don't want to get into this unless you all have some
specific questions. I mean, certainly this can get bogged down and get rather boring. So maybe
a couple highlights that utility authority looks very good. It's profitable. Scott, it's got
sufficient reserves. The general fund is probably talking to Lindsay. It's probably on the
minimum side of acceptable as far as reserves. So I think you all have been working to try to build
those up. And so just know that it's okay, but we'd like to see maybe a little bit better if you
can get it that way. Really beyond that as far as numbers in here, nothing in here that just
struck me out that I thought I needed to point out to you all, nothing negative, nothing that needs to be
corrected. So I don't know if you all have any questions on this document. Certainly now is the time
to ask Anna Vicki, I don't know if you didn't have a chance to look at it. So that makes it a little
hard to prepare. I don't want our general fund reserves. How do we compare it to other communities of
a lifetime? Probably being pretty similar. You know, it's similar, maybe even your own personal
finances. How much can you have a reserve if you lost a job? If something came up, health, medical,
whatever, or even an opportunity, do you have some reserves? And so I would maybe say six months or so of
revenue is kind of another road number, some may say the more some say less. You know, it probably a little bit
under three months of reserves. And so again, that's not horrible. It's not horrible at all. And so again,
you're probably pretty similar. Now again, on the utility side, that is very well, that's doing
very well. And so certainly there could be some compensation there, you know, some play between the two.
So anything else on this before? No, no findings, no negative findings at all. That would be in the
second letter. Well, he and the first one too, but no, they're not. They could show a couple of places actually.
And in this document, they are auditing. It's clean, or maybe the unmodified opinion. It's what
everyone gets this expects to see. They want to see. So that's good. There's also a report in the back.
That's required by the state that deals with your controls and compliance. There's no findings there.
So if they were going to be some findings, they would most likely be in that report at the back. So there's nothing
in there. The second document that I just handed out, this is required by our auditing
profession by our standards to get to the governing body. And so if there were some issues that
needed to be brought to your attention, they would be in here. And really, there's nothing in here.
It's really just here's the issue, and there's nothing under it.
You know, just describing here is kind of the issue and then there's nothing there. So it's really just the blooded plate letter essentially
So that's what we like to see that's what you'll like to see that's what we like to give
So so good job
Again the Crawford's who did really good work
Love working with Lindsay she was excellent as well and I don't know Lindsay if she remembers. We were here again
six seven eight years ago and it's come a long way since then as far as improving and so I'm
I'm delighted as I can be to see how much better it's gotten
We appreciate that and we know we can always have more reserve
And that is something that we're focused on trying to build very good. I'm going to switch you point that out any questions
Okay, well being in staff thanks all for the excellent job that you did and working with that
All right, thank you. Okay, thank you sir
I
In order to choose
Not subscription customers mitigation rates for fire versus five of services and we're feeling parts of ordinance 1379
What I'm here tonight to do is ask you to reveal the ordinance that is currently on the books for
Firecodes and the county and replace it with the ordinance that supplies for
Mitigation rates and it's based on non-MSUA customer and also on the known subscription
Destination for filling
Remindings and Robert this is day
Really the information you talked to us about a couple of times and then kind of refining and working on
Correct, yes
That's correct. I think that was mainly the second part that was the county
You know involving our customers outside the city a little bit still in our city fire district
Any questions for Robert
So if this has time to take back immediately
You know what people outside of the word if we've got a letter that is a
Question based answer backslatter and it will answer some of the questions and we'll send that out
And I don't I don't think it'll take effect immediately. It'll be like 30 days
I'm probably watching how about something the same thing. I've received the words if I'll get here
I'm gonna get the right one
And there's not a merge calls on the agenda
Or horse or
that we hadn't been asking for a word of words, so.
Okay.
Not just you.
We still have to turn it down.
We need to get our work done.
I'm going to get notice this out.
Everything.
Okay.
So.
Robert, what you're asking for?
Just a vote to approve.
Or December 2017, 2001.
It's also part of that repeals.
14.
17.
Correct.
Yes.
We have a motion.
Okay.
And second.
Second.
Roll, roll, please.
Question.
What?
Do it.
Question.
And on an 18 discussion with fire district manager, Robert.
Okay.
A boner discussion at the chief's meeting.
We talked about, you know, what we were looking at in, according to what other
departments in the county have established for billing.
Right.
That discussion, the fire chief and wine dog ask if we would be interested in taking
east of town, 590 route to 600 route, which would encompass all of the P.O.
Rio region area.
And there are about 10 miles away.
And we're less than 5 miles away from that district.
So that would benefit them.
And it would possibly give us about 80 more subscribers to her.
What is there on the graph?
What is there IS?
So I think there are five.
So it would really help if ever within the five miles, you know, they could get part of our
three rating.
Yes.
And, you know, 10 miles for them to travel in the chief is the one that said, you know, really
looking at this.
It's probably best if for them if this would be possible.
And would us, say, annexing an order of what use annexing them into our fire district,
would that affect our IS so negatively in any way?
No.
Now, everything within five miles will get our three rating if third would fill 1,000 feet of a water supply.
So it would benefit them.
And so tonight, you're just looking for guidance from us as we wanted to make you aware of it.
And I believe this, this is required actually the county vision.
Yes.
So it does need to go through the county commission to be able to put it into our fire district
down, but it's working with Chief Wright looking at this as he explained it.
I think from the standards of the people that are there, our fire services and better protection
in this area is a good look.
And when I really appreciate it, I just speak that very cooperative.
Chief, if you were also at that meeting, we're going to talk about the fee structure for the subscriptions.
Okay.
The meeting that we talked to was in November.
The next one's getting right down.
And that's when we were going to have that discussion, and then, yeah, so the stuff that you're going to be
going to be mailing out, you're going to mail out that, knowing the cost of the subscription.
I would like the cost to be $65.
And that's, it goes anywhere from 30 to 100.
And so what you're going to talk about is you and then propose at least to the group of chiefs that you have a unit for now.
65 is enough that you want.
Yes, RP.
Okay.
Annual.
Yes, correct.
Okay.
Any questions?
How's one of those?
Does that P.C. have a first responder?
Yes.
That's fire.
Well, it'll fire in first responder services from the fire department.
I don't know.
Okay.
So we'll proceed accordingly, but we wanted to have this discussion with you, so we're aware of that.
All right.
Thank you.
Hi to 19 is proposed charter changes.
I don't know that.
I thought that we had to, I felt really accurate.
I read this after not looking at it for a month.
I had to change.
But as it turns out, his logic was right in mind.
So, at least that's what he thinks.
Well, see, I did find an extra, I did find one type of end, this to repeat.
So certainly we can talk about this if you want to.
There were a couple of issues that I did ask me to look at it.
It was simply blank with to make sure that it was clarity.
So then 10 years from now, a question comes up.
It's probably clear how something gets to dealt with.
And then there was the issue of the language relating to Vicki's award.
And he's going to think the language he's got in there is correct.
So there was nothing of substance beyond that that I had to say anything to anybody else.
Let's talk about it.
Thank you.
Okay.
And we're going to move on to item 20, which was an election resolution calling for cleaning and ordering and non-partisan special election.
To repeal the current charter for the city of Miami and adopt the news proposed city charter in lieu there of.
And then has resolution language related to that.
Then is there any reason why we can't go ahead and pass the resolution even if there's a very minor change in the current language?
would you prefer that way? We can do that. It simply has to be presented to the election board by
January 20th.
The resolution we can go ahead and approve calling to the election.
So I think you're in your mind your question about the resolution versus the proclamation.
Probably.
Because I went through that same song in dance.
Actually, this is drafted for the one document to serve in both capacity.
Probably the better way to proceed with me to make sure that the
proposed charter change is exactly as you want it.
And then you approve the resolution at that point.
Calling for the election and proclaiming the election at the same time.
So it would just be some minor changes. Probably just a date change to this.
This resolution.
It sounds like you're recommending that we don't take action on this tonight.
We wait for the meeting on the 17th.
I think it would be cleaner if we if there is the possibility of making any changes to the charter.
That we do that at the same time.
I would propose that we do that as there is a check show to doing that.
So we're going to take no action on item 20.
Item 21 is the election resolution calling for calling for claiming and ordering non-partisan general election for the office of mayor of the city of Miami.
And I confused that on this one too.
I told him that Vicki didn't have to run and she did have to run and she didn't.
In fact, she does because she was appointed just happened to be the first meeting in May, which is when people normally take office.
And so she was not included on this resolution.
She'd say for the mayor and for her award.
And so I don't propose that we take action on this on the 17th.
And she's allowed in to amend that one book.
Any questions on that or concerns?
We're going to get you off in, Vicki.
So that's as high as 22, which is discussed with Miami City Center, a rehab project.
And it's got a lot of names by it.
But if you don't have enough first, I'm going to go from there.
It depends on how much discussion you guys want to have.
Okay, so we're here tonight to look at the fuller plans.
Where we're at.
I'm kind of going to get you all finger prints on it and input blessing on the play itself.
I want to give you a little bit of background.
Back in 2015, the CMAR process was bedded and
to be a resolution. In August of 2016, the Council approved a CMAR contract with
Crossline and then workload number 13 with GH2 at Architects. The next process after
we're okay with this plan is to do start doing the detail, which is the mechanical
and electrical and plumbing MEP is what they refer to as. They will come back to you
with a gross maximum price with all the detail and you guys will approve that.
And it will be up to $2 million dollars depending on what we come up with.
There is the budget. There this year, the $2 million, it's going to come out the ready-day fund.
The first repainment back to the ready-day fund is going to occur also this year,
around 26,000 in exchange and then the plan is to provide for six subsequent annual repayments back
305,000 in the coming year's budgets. We did visit with every end user that is
represented on the drawing. They've all had a chance to give input. Several times actually,
the rehab should include add actually live to the building itself for guessing 50 years. If it's
probably maintained after everything's replaced because there's some significant things that are going to be replaced.
One would be re-roofing the remaining part of the Civic Center. If you guys remember we did
re-roof half of the Civic Center last year. It also includes upgrading the project areas
electrical systems and HVAC. And those three projects alone are a significant portion of the budget itself.
It will also create an open floor plan. You can kind of see this hallway. We'll go away. That's kind
of the biggest thing. Everything will be open. Those still be offices that the center part will be open.
It will improve some security. Not shown if on down is the you can see where court
right there is where court will be moved. The doors into the banquet room which are just
east a little bit. Those are not shown to be part of the plan that they are part of the plan to be
those double doors, big glass doors, those need to be re-done. And then the door is going into utility
building will also be re-done. That is actually part of the plan.
Jill, you're saying court that's also challenging to change. Yes. Yes. You're right.
What is not included is anything to be done to any of the bathrooms. They're fine. They're not included
as any kind of upgrade of any kind. They're workable and they're fine as they stand today.
And the council slash court run that's on there. Where is it in this building current?
We're finances. So they're in higher place there. So when people go into court or people come into
council meetings that walk in the front door and they're right there. So we're showing where the front door
This is an old drawer and it has the old four-year-old and I'm just going to have a front.
So this is still be the front doors that are currently there now.
They will be upgraded to the ADA compatible door.
The other door she's talking about is here.
We have an additional capital improvement project now that we're trying to stop working on.
To redo the ramp and the stairs.
You see out there.
And so the staircase and the ramp will be put back.
We're going to try to push those through these doors.
That way they'll have this access in the year.
And it keeps them in a public area where the offices will mainly be locked down.
Which is kind of in our go-all along.
It's a secure the offices.
So all the hash mark areas.
That's just going to become open space.
That is not part of the plan.
The money will not be used on the hash.
That's a very strange idea.
Yes.
In the plan.
We had a tour of our customer service area.
The colors, the finishes, that's kind of what we're going to be looking for in many areas.
We keep the kitchen.
We'll be keeping a caterer's kitchen.
We'll be a smaller.
We're going to do the way with all the old appliances.
We'll go through just a lot of commercial refrigerator and freezer.
And then go to a hot place.
We'll be similar to what you've seen at the moment.
Yeah.
Okay.
So we're going to talk about taking it out.
We did.
But there's still.
Since we've done some paintings and brought the new heat and hair in,
it's due to the bankrupt.
It's really kind of kind of a big live.
We've been getting a lot of advance.
We've got about something that we've got in the next month.
The dog shows back.
The car creaking off.
Just back.
The high school's utilized.
So rather than doing a way with it,
we thought we could utilize it.
Play the smaller.
A caterer's kitchen.
Yeah.
We still have access.
And you said I do.
One of the questions that was asked.
I think the rotary pancake fee was.
It's some of that stuff.
Like the really stuff.
Going to disappear.
It will.
So they need to be.
We'll be going to find a different way.
We'll have fun at different locations.
Or there are.
Or the little grittles.
So they could grab a little pancake fee.
Okay.
No, somebody's here.
You've already talked to him.
Got all of them.
Come on.
I think there's a lot of space.
You've been.
Yeah.
Find another way.
You know.
And I hope is.
What the.
When we upgrade the electrical.
The rotary pancake fee this year would blow a breaker.
We could not find it anywhere.
It was in HR's closet.
You know, we would never look for it.
So that's kind of a part.
process will move it up. That's great. Not that I'll see. No lots of lot of
water. 9-11. Staying in the upgrades, did it?
It all depends on money.
I'm going to leave it off in the past base. Our lantern goal is to move dispatch
down into the sea so that becomes a sweet above the emergency
operations. And 9-11 dispatch. And then that would free up some room in the
police department for offices as well so they're not as crowded.
Again, it's just how far we can stretch our dollars right now.
So, Joe, you mentioned that in all our drill here on this ad, what work
that network come from? Well, during the budget season, we talked about just
taking $2 billion in doing the rehab and that was what was approaching the budget.
So, we're trying to work whatever plan we can. We have a list. We actually have a list of
things and that's what I think that is remembering our list. It's prioritized and
we're starting with this and seeing what we're going to get because we have an
idea. And then we're going to keep going with that one.
And as was stated before, we're talking about that amount of money. A lot of that money,
in this space, it's going to be just basic stabilization of a building.
We're grouping system, heating and air system, things such as that.
Probably the gutting and the new offices, that will be probably some of the lesser cost
as part of this. But if you remember, I remember seeing them before I became
manager of these pictures, that the horse tross upstairs and, you know, the sea was
getting in, you'll notice that's a thing of past. That's that we just started reinvesting
in the building. I think it's being a lot of business right now. Also, I think the roofing
that we're talking about also who is a gymnasium. Yes, absolutely.
So, that you'll look at it from the outside. You see some cracking and things like that.
And I think as part of this process, we've recognized the gym. It's really a gym for this
community. There are a lot of people on the sea maintained. Depending on
you know, we're around on budget, I think, and several of you have mentioned.
You'd like to see us looking at the possibility of air conditioning. So, we're
at least having a little better airflow. So, it could be used during the summer months.
So, that would be something that we'll keep in mind as well.
Is there a heating upgrade being done? I did it one time.
It was one last leg. We kind of bandated it along. I didn't know if that was part of
We're in the MVP. We're looking at upgrading all of the organizations.
So, we're only trying to eliminate the same boiler.
We're not going to go to more of a cell in there. So, yes.
Today, you see it with crossover. You can get any questions about
the price in every place that you've just done.
That's good. You can get it done for half a day.
You wouldn't say half.
So, we get a little bit more details on the MVP.
That's the foundation. That's the big take of it.
So, we really need to get our radiator around that today.
So, if you guys want to insert it then.
the one concern you're seeing is a lot of inventory right now, so we get the engineers involved
and the time to talk about what has been done, what needs to be brought up to the
objective, the upstairs, we're not doing the way with anything of the upstairs, we'll be putting
things upstairs that the general public doesn't normally have to access, because one of the
key things we have is a 80-edic compliance, and by adding, for example, a lot of the stuff
there's really not a 80-edic compliance, we do reasonable accommodations so many needs to see
me and they can't come up with the stairs, I'll walk downstairs, so we'll probably
have such some of our operations up there that we need to make such as that that really
don't interact with the public in this building, and we'll probably also maintain the
staff rooms and things such as that for general meetings, so it's like a lot of people that
are upstairs and they don't think downstairs, that's what we're trying to have is that
it's being in all different areas we can all work together, we do need to change the mapping though
for the city manager, it's supposed to be an orange, city attorneys in the red, same manager needs
to be an orange other than that, we're pretty happy.
Well, with the city attorney it is.
Oh, yeah, we have an LSU first part.
We have some closing drive through, there's no need to ever, we're just looking to lean that plane there.
One thing that we're looking at right now is the drop box in the drive through, we used to be there
and we're looking at the idea of turning that into some very short, short, short term parking,
where sometimes we've seen that some people just want to park there, run a bill and get it received,
come out.
So we think if we did something like that, it would be a little more customer friendly for people
needing to run in and not having to walk up the ranch.
So we're looking at that as a possibility right now and trying to have the proper signage to say
on the outside lane that your drop box, the inside lane, you can run inside real quick.
Yeah, exactly five minutes, something like that.
And the other portion.
What about the computer room?
It's nice signage.
What about, do you think to the phone or the name, it's the HFAC.
Okay.
The many splits you're going to go away in.
I'd also like to just say something, just a thank you to Kevin and his crew.
Because over the last few months that we decided to stay here,
it's amazing.
The TLC, they give it a building, just a cup of paint.
Yeah, some things got mended that needed to be.
and all that. It's just so nice to walk in the building. It just kind of seems to come back to
a lot. It's not really that much. And again, doing it for our staff, but I'm going to
just paint some good work. So, more than that.
All right. Thank you, I'll earn much.
So, we're getting our next report. I guess that's the next update.
We will give it a change to probably tomorrow.
Is there a thing to be anywhere to have three months to turn around on the MEP?
Okay. We're hoping we can push that little quicker, but that's kind of where they're at.
You can probably three months at a time.
I'm going to sound like.
All right. Thank you.
Item 23 is due business in any business.
There's 40 more staff reports. 25 is mayor and council announcements.
I don't know about that.
This is actually, I check my mail.
I got this nice letter from this girl, but I'm not ready to be.
Dear mayor, my name is Heather.
My favorite color is pink.
If you need to help fix and stuff, I leave it my email from home on Bajsters.
Merry Christmas.
Love how they're jobs.
Yes, what is your name?
I'd like to know.
This is sure we're going to make it.
We're going to buy it.
So, thank you.
I appreciate that.
I'm on that note.
I told the other council to reserve it.
And I'm going to file for office for reelection in February.
So, that's all I got to say.
Anything else?
Could that cost you again?
I'm also going to make a lot of that.
I guess we have 26 to send me in.
Just very quickly.
I'd like to turn it over to them because he's made some very subtle changes.
I don't think anybody does it on your agenda.
I think it's going to help us in the future.
We have implemented a new numbering system.
You might notice the resolutions that were on the agenda today were
CC, which is City Council 2017.
You might guess that that's a year.
Bash 01 and 02.
And then we continue that.
Do the same thing with the ordinances.
We'll be the plan.
So, I sure make it a whole lot easier to try to find something
who we're going back to look at prior history when you're looking for
resolution in 689.
You have no idea when that was.
And so, it...
Our thinking process would be that it was just the easier for everybody to track what we're doing and where we did it.
We think 50 years from now on.
Yeah, it really was all fixed up.
And they're going to look at this and say, well, those people 50 years ago did a great effect.
And it was a logical time to do it.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
You know, during the old 7-5, there were afterwards trying to find stuff and some of it got forced away.
Okay.
Now we are to adjourn it.
We, how do you point that?
We're going to adjourn it.
Second.
We're going to.